YAO-HUNG HUBERT TSAI

♦ https://yaohungt.github.io ♦ (412) 736-2674 ♀ yaohungt@cs.cmu.edu

RESEARCH SUMMARY

My primary research interests lie in the general areas of Machine Learning, in particular Deep Learning and Statistics. I focus on providing principled and systematic understandings of cutting edge machine learning methodologies. On this basis, I develop algorithms and computational models to improve the performance, generalization, and interpretability of data representations. Applications of my research span Core Machine Learning (CoreML), Computer Vision (CV), Natural Language Processing (NLP), and Speech Processing (SP).

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA, USA

Aug 2016 - Aug 2021 (Expected)

• Ph.D. in Machine Learning Department within School of Computer Science (GPA: 4.08/4.3)

National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan

Aug 2010 - Jun 2014

- B.S. in Electrical Engineering (graduated with Department Honors) (GPA: 4.17/4.3)
- Presidential Awards in 2011/2012/2014, Undergraduate Ceremony Representative (top 10 students out of 230)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

Graduate Research Assistant, Carnegie Mellon University

Aug 2016 - Present

- <u>CoreML</u> Providing an information-theoretical explanation for the effectiveness of the self-supervised learned representations [ICLR'21A]. The explanation inspires new loss function designs [ICLR'21A, ICLR'21B].
- **CoreML** Tractable and scalable mutual information estimation [ICLR'21B, NeurIPS'20].
- CV/NLP/SP Analyzing human language from spoken text, facial attributes, and tones of voice [EMNLP'20, ACL'19, ICLR'19].
 - CV/NLP Learning modality-invariant feature space across vision and text [ICCV'17, N-LLD'17].
 - CoreML Deep neural networks regularization [NeurIPS'19] and Transformer architecture explanation [EMNLP'19].
 - Advisor: Dr. Ruslan Salakhutdinov & Dr. Louis-Philippe Morency

Graduate Research Intern, Facebook AI Research

Summer 2020

- **<u>sp</u>** Improving and providing a better understanding for self-supervised speech representation learning. Works include 1) incorporating temporal structures within representations, 2) unifying different loss function designs, and 3) introducing weak supervision from fast and cheap clustering [N-SAS'20].
 - Host: Dr. Abdelrahman Mohamed

Graduate Research Intern, Apple Inc.

Summer 2019

- cv 3D object recognition from multi-sensory data, spanning LiDAR, Radar, and RGB sensors.
- CV Improving the scalability and stability of routing mechanism in Capsule networks [ICLR'20].
 - Host: Dr. Nitish Srivastava & Dr. Ruslan Salakhutdinov

Graduate Research Intern, Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence

Summer 2018

- CV/NLP Video spatiotemporal relationships modeling for common sense retrieval [CVPR'19].
 - Host: Dr. Santosh Kumar Divvala & Dr. Ali Farhadi

Graduate Research Intern, Microsoft Research

Summer 2017

CoreML Temporal order discovery in unordered dataset [N-TSW'17].

• Host: Dr. Nebojsa Jojic

Visiting Scholar, RIKEN AIP/ Kyoto University

Winter 2017, Winter 2018, Winter 2019

- <u>CoreML</u> Optimal transportation, high-dimensional feature selection, semi-supervised mutual information estimation, and linear-time distribution divergence measurement [see https://yaohungt.github.io/research.html].
 - Host: Dr. Makoto Yamada & Dr. Masashi Sugiyama

Research Assistant, CITI, Academia Sinica

Aug 2015 - Aug 2016

- CV Domain Adaptation for Visual Object Recognition [CVPR'16, AAAI'16].
 - Host: Dr. Yu-Chiang Frank Wang

- ICLR'21A Y.-H. H. Tsai, Y. Wu, R. Salakhutdinov, L.-P. Morency. "Self-supervised Learning from a Multi-view Perspective", International Conference on Learning Representations, 2021.
- ICLR'21B Y.-H. H. Tsai*, M. Q. Ma*, M. Yang, H. Zhao, L.-P. Morency, R. Salakhutdinov. "Self-supervised Representation Learning with Relative Predictive Coding", *International Conference on Learning Representations*, 2021.
- N-SAS'20 W.-N. Hsu, Y.-H. H. Tsai, B. Bolte, R. Salakhutdinov, A. Mohamed. "HUBERT: How much can a bad teacher benefit ASR pre-training?", NeurIPS Self-Supervised Learning for Speech and Audio Processing Workshop, 2020.
- NeurIPS'20 Y.-H. H. Tsai, H. Zhao, M. Yamada, L.-P. Morency, R. Salakhutdinov. "Neural Methods for Point-wise Dependency Estimation", Neural Information Processing Systems, 2020. (Spotlight Presentation)
- EMNLP'20 Y.-H. H. Tsai*, M. Q. Ma*, M. Yang*, R. Salakhutdinov, L.-P. Morency. "Multimodal Routing: Improving Local and Global Interpretability of Multimodal Language Analysis", *Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing*, 2020.
 - ICLR'20 Y.-H. H. Tsai, N. Srivastava, H. Goh, R. Salakhutdinov. "Capsules with Inverted Dot-Product Attention Routing", International Conference on Learning Representations, 2020.
- NeurIPS'19 H. Zhao*, Y.-H. H. Tsai*, R. Salakhutdinov, G. Gordon. "Learning Neural Networks with Adaptive Regularization", Neural Information Processing Systems, 2019.
- EMNLP'19 Y.-H. H. Tsai, S. Bai, M. Yamada, L.-P. Morency, R. Salakhutdinov. "Transformer Dissection: A Unified Understanding of Transformer's Attention via the Lens of Kernel", *Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing*, 2019.
 - ACL'19 Y.-H. H. Tsai*, S. Bai*, P. P. Liang, J. Z. Kolter, L.-P. Morency, R. Salakhutdinov. "Multimodal Transformer for Unaligned Multimodal Language Sequences", Association for Computational Linguistics, 2019.
 - ICLR'19 Y.-H. H. Tsai*, P. P. Liang*, A. Zadeh, L.-P. Morency, R. Salakhutdinov. "Learning Factorized Multimodal Representations", *International Conference on Learning Representations*, 2019.
 - CVPR'19 Y.-H. H. Tsai, S. K. Divvala, L.-P. Morency, R. Salakhutdinov, A. Farhadi. "Video Relationship Reasoning using Gated Spatio-Temporal Energy Graph", Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2019.
- N-TSW'17 Y.-H. H. Tsai, H. Zhao, R. Salakhutdinov, N. Jojic. "Learning Markov Chain in Unordered Dataset", NeurIPS Time Series Workshop, 2017. (Oral Presentation)
- ICCV'17 Y.-H. H. Tsai, L.-K. Huang, R. Salakhutdinov. "Learning Robust Visual-Semantic Embeddings", *International Conference on Computer Vision*, 2017.
- N-LLD'17 Y.-H. H. Tsai, R. Salakhutdinov. "Improving One-Shot Learning through Fusing Side Information", NeurIPS Learning with Limited Labeled Data: Weak Supervision and Beyond, 2017.
- CVPR'16 Y.-H. H. Tsai, Y.-R. Yeh, Y.-C. F. Wang. "Learning Cross-Domain Landmarks for Heterogeneous Domain Adaptation", Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2016.
- AAAI'16 Y.-H. H. Tsai, C.-A. Hou, W.-Y. Chen, Y.-R. Yeh, Y.-C. F. Wang. "Domain-Constraint Transfer Coding for Imbalanced Unsupervised Domain Adaptation", Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence, 2016.

SELECTED HONORS & AWARDS

Facebook Fellowship, Facebook	2020
AI2 Fellowship, Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence	2018
Government Scholarship to Study Abroad (GSSA), Taiwan Ministry of Education	2016
National Representative Honorable Mention, International Physics Olympiad Selection Camp	2009/2010
1st Runner-Up/Third Prize, Regional/National Physics Olympiad for Senior High School	2009
Honorable Mention, International Junior Science Olympiad Selection Camp	2008

TEACHING EXPERIENCES & PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

Head Teaching Assistant, Carnegie Mellon University

Spring 2019

• 10-716 Advanced Machine Learning / New Statistical Machine Learning (Instructor: Dr. Pradeep Ravikumar)

Teaching Assistant, Carnegie Mellon University

 $Fall\ 2017$

• 10-707 Topics in Deep Learning (Instructor: Dr. Ruslan Salakhutdinov)

CMU Machine Learning Department: PhD Admission, Master Admission, Speaking Skills.

Conference and Journal Reviewer: ICML, NeurIPS, ICLR, ICCV, CVPR, AISTATS, ACL, EMNLP, TPAMI, TIP.